Nicholos Palmer

nicholospalmer@gmail.com * 704-414-0302 * New York, NY * Portfolio

Summary

Creative content manager with experience in organizing digital assets, creating web-based content, building email marketing campaigns and improving webpage usability. Budding usability expert, 3d modeler, and poet aiming to apprentice at Creative X and foster my creative writing and program management forte.

Work Experience

Web Coordinator

Carnegie Endowment for International Peace | remote

Oct 2021 - Present

- Achieved an 8% increase in email subscribers during 2023, after spearheading email marketing strategy improvement.
- Manage content using HTML/CSS and Payload CMS, contributing to a 24% increase in digital readership in 2023.
- Achieved a 20% rise in attendance of 2022 Nuclear Policy Conference event after incorporating UX discoverability principles (improving call-to-action prompts and component hierarchy in email design)
- Coordinate cross-functional teams in launching global campaigns, ensuring timely and effective communication across different departments resulting in improved workflow strategy.
- Optimize website performance and email marketing strategy by monitoring web analytics, identifying opportunities for optimization, and delivering insights aligned with the team's strategic objectives.
- Produce training materials and facilitate onboarding sessions for new employees on CMS usage resulting in efficient, improving operational support across global teams.

Office Assistant

Town of Chapel Hill / Chapel Hill, NC

Aug 2019 - Oct 2021

- Achieved 30% decrease in inbound customer phone calls and an increase in user time-on-site after spearheading website redesign for local government website.
- Served as web steward and helped the Town's Information Architecture committee with website layout, SEO best practices and digital assets management and UX/Plain Language research.

Projects

Redesign of PackLane.com package design editor

- Identify customer pain point relating to usability of online editor environment and research customer segments impacted by usability improvements
- Using Figma, created lo-fi wireframe and user journey map describing updated design feature

Skills

Adobe CC • HTML/CSS • Figma • Marketo • Monday.com • Splash Event Marketing • Blender (student) • Email Marketing • Conversion Optimization • SEO • Project Management • Communication • Responsive Design • Detailed-focused • Storytelling • Building Partnerships

Education

Northeastern University | P/T Graduate Certificate | Usability

Wake Technical Community College | Certificate | Web Development 1

University of North Carolina at Pembroke | Bachelor of Arts | Political Science

August

August

August 2024-Present March 2020-Aug 2020 August 2012-May 2016